McKersie, Robert B., Additional Papers /4284
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Robert B. McKersie Additional Papers
1975-2010
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
McKersie, Robert B.
/4284
3 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
8159473
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 01, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Robert B. McKersie, DBA
Professor of Management, Emeritus, Sloan School of Management, Massachusetts Institute of Technology
Robert McKersie is professor emeritus of management at the MIT Sloan School of Management, where he has been since 1980. Prior to his time at MIT, he served as dean of the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University, and as a faculty member of the Graduate School of Business at the University of Chicago. McKersie has served on several presidential commissions at the national level, is a member of the National Academy of Arbitrators, and was president of the National Industrial Relations Research Association (now the Labor and Employment Relations Association). He is the author of numerous articles relating to human resources, industrial relations, and operations management.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4027 OHM: ILR History Interviews /4032 AV: ILR School 20th Annual Wilhelm Weinberg Labor-Management Public Interest Seminar Audio-Visual Materials /4033: Robert B. McKersie Files /4054: ILR School Dean's Office Additional Files /4071: Robert B. McKersie Additional Files /4142: Robert B. McKersie Additional Papers /4297: ILR School Biography Files /4309: M. Gardner Clark Papers /4343: Robert B. McKersie Collections 6007: U.S. Department of Labor Office of American Workplace Labor Management Cooperation Collected Publications 6213: Robert B. McKersie Additional Files 6325: Robert B. McKersie PIE Trucking Company Files 6326: Robert B. McKersie Research Collection for "The Impact of Collective Bargaining on Management" 6327: Robert B. McKersie Nassau County Multi-Municipality Productivity Project Files
McKersie, Robert B.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations
8159473
- Inland Steel board of directors papers: Unpublished biography of Irving Ives by Emmet O'Brien. (Box 1)
  - Irving M. Ives: An Upstate Progressive Pages 1-300 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Irving M. Ives: An Upstate Progressive Pages 301-539 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agreements: United Steel, Paper and Forestry, Rubber Manufacturing, Energy, Allied Industrial and Service Workers International Union, 2005-2008 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Union Directors Meeting, 1984-1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Business Week and Papers, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - UND Logistics, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Inland, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Inland, 1999-2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Productivity Improvement Implementation folder 1, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Productivity Improvement Implementation folder 2, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Expenses, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Audit - Expenses (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Current, 1999-2004 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - United States Securities and Exchange Commission, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 2002-2009 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - United Steelworkers, 2002-2008 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Magazines, 2002-2006 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ispat Island Inc., 2005 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Mittel Steel USA Inc., 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2008 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Essays and Papers, 1999-2009 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Airline industry research papers; Harvard University-HUCTW negotiations, 2007. (Box 2)
  - Airline, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Airline, 2005-2007 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Up in the Air, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Airlines, 1999-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Airline, 2001-2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Labor Relations and Human Resource Management in the Airline Industry, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Labor Relations and Human Resource Management in the Airline Industry, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Airline Correspondence, Notes, Clippings, 1998-2009 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Out of the Ashes: Building an Effective Labor Relations System in Airlines Transparencies, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Airline Industry Slides, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - MIT Global Airline Industry Program, 2005-2008 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - ALPA, 1996-2002 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Airline Industry Papers, 1993-2004 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Airline Industry Papers, 2005-2008 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Agreements, 1998-2009 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Airline Industry Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Harvard University - HUCTW, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Harvard, 2004-2007 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Harvard Planning Work, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - General Plan, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Career Mobility and Employment, 2001-2007 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Ames, 2007-2010 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Harvard, 2004-2007 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Side Table Chartering, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Preliminary Findings, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Poster (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Strategic Negotiations research papers, mostly railroads; HERE Atlantic City strike, Harrah's. (Box 3)
  - Railroad Project, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Railroads (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Union Pacific, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Burlington Northern, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Conrail, 1981-1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Long Island Railroad, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Guilford Transportation, 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Paper Industry, 1975-1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Railroads, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Conrail, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Conrail, 1990-1998 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Railroads, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Union Pacific, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Trade and Industry, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Presidential Emergency Board, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Strategic Negotiations Research Papers, 1985-1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Papers (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 3, Folder 19)